Max Skewes

Portland, OR 97215 | 503 477-2975 | maxskewes@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://maxskewes.github.io/Portfolio/

Github: https://github.com/maxskewes/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxskewes/

Full-Stack Bootcamp Graduate from the University of Oregon with experience in graphic design. Skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJs and responsive web design, with strengths in original design/layout, meeting deadlines, teamwork and communication skills. Known to have a positive demeanor and enjoys problem solving/resolution, with an eagerness to learn new skills in order to facilitate positive team-driven environments, resulting in user-friendly and more efficient experiences on the web.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, MySQLdb, Express, MongoDb, Handelbars.js, ReactJS

Applications: Visual Studio Code

Projects

NBA FANBOI: Fan App

Github: https://github.com/maxskewes/NBA-Fanboi

Deployed: https://nbafanboi.herokuapp.com/

An app designed by a team of four. It features realtime scores, stats and standings, as well as allowing the user to star favorite players.

• Duties included front-end design, logo design, conceptualization, presentation

Built with: Handlebars, Javascript, Node, MySql, CSS, Bootstrap

WANDERLUST: Travel App

Github: https://github.com/maxskewes/Wanderlust
Deployed: https://github.com/maxskewes/Wanderlust

An app designed by a team of three. It features a responsive map and allows users to find information on perspective travel destinations.

• Duties included front-end design, original artwork/text, conceptualization, presentation

Built with: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Materialize, Open Weather API, Google Maps API, and Google Places API.

Experience

CO-FOUNDER/ORGANIZER/DESIGNER

2017 - present | Portland, OR

Bridgetown Bluegrass Festival (501c3)

Non-profit founded by myself with one other, working as a strong two-person team to develop and grow a large Portland-based music festival. Taking on leadership positions, managing volunteers and performers, venue sourcing, band recruitment and all other aspects of event planning.

- Increased gross income from \$12,000 in 2017 to \$21,700 in 2019
- All graphic design, logos, layout and original artwork for album production, merchandise and promotion
- Auditioned/accepted popular bands and created graphically designed promotional material (including merchandise) which helped boost attendendance from approx. 500 people in 2017, to approx. 900 people in 2019
- Coordinated the enlisting, training and scheduling of 30+ volunteers.
- Donated over \$15,000 to charitable organizations, most notably Do-Good Multnomah's Women's Shelter

BLUEGRASS BANJO PLAYER

Scratchdog Stringband

2015 - present | Portland, OR

Professional musician in an internationally touring band.

- Received a U.S. Government Grant and Humanitarian Visa to tour Eastern Russia in 2018 in an educational & diplomatic capacity
- Working as a close-knit team to run our band as a business
- All graphic design, logos, layout and original artwork for album production, merchandise and promotion
- Invited Diplomatic Cultural Ambassadors via. the U.S. State Department
- Invited to multiple schools/colleges, domestic and abroad, to give Master Classes/Lectures
- Building/repairing/maintaining instruments requiring a keen eye for detail

BREWER

Cider Riot!
Burnside Brewing

2015 - 2019 | Portland, OR

2011 - 2018 | Portland, OR

Roots Brewing

2008 - 2011 | Portland, OR

Alameda Brewing

2006 - 2009 | Portland, OR

Working with two to five people teams to conceptualize, manufacture, monitor and produce consumer-ready fermented beverages. Strong and open communication essential to time-management and fostering a productive team environment.

- Uniting several disciplines for a single purpose: mathematics for conversion and calculation, production physics, fermentation chemistry
- Creativity required in recipe formulation, naming products and collaboration with packaging design
- Multiple Bronze, Silver and Gold metals from domestic and international brewing competitions
- Bookkeeping essential to reporting records to the TTB (formally FTA)

Education

CODING BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE:

University of Oregon

2019 - 2020 | Portland, OR

An immersive, 24-week program in full stack web development with training in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, Bookshelf.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, Git, Java, and more.

CERTIFICATE OF IRISH STUDIES/ARTS/MUSIC

University College Cork (Coláiste na hOllscoile Corcaigh)

2000 - 2004 | Cork, Ireland

First Class Honours in Irish Language (Gaeilge), Music Performance and Composition.

ASSOCIATES DEGREE OF LIBERAL ARTS

Marylhurst University

1998-2000 | Marylhurst, OR

Two year Liberal Arts degree program.